Guide to the Randolph Linsly Simpson African-American Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series I. Visual Material
  - STEREOGRAPHS
    - Studio unknown Stamped recto, "452 -- Perry's Victory on Lake Erie, 1813" cropped, albumen reproduction of William Powell's "Perry's Victory on Lake Erie." Stereograph, ivory card, circa 1879 (Box 12, Folder 578)
      Item #310
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Photographer's identification stamped recto. Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 579)
      Man bending over before stack of bricks, ax in right hand, touching brick with left. In ink, verso, "731. Bricklayer"
      Item #311
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Photographer's identification stamped recto. Mounted verso, "900 A Home-Made Cycle. The cycle craze has reached even the remote country districts...." Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 580)
      Four young boys on what appears to be a beach. One pushes toddler on one-wheel cycle; third stands holding a ball; fourth watches with arms akimbo.
      Item #312
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Photographer's identification stamped recto. Mounted in negative, recto, "615 Scene in the South." Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 581)
      Small building with large roof overhang sits along dirt street; spectators at either edge of image. Advertisement for the American Tobacco Company stamped verso.
      Item #313
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Photographer's identification stamped recto. In ink, verso, "633 Husking Hominy." Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 582)
      Staged domestic scene: several women, some seated, a few kneeling, work in a circle; three toddlers and a man watch from the outskirts.
      Item #314
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Photographer's identification stamped recto. In ink, verso, "728. Old Moses." Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 583)
      Man with grocer's hand truck stands in front of mansion outside iron wrought fence. "[?] Grocer" painted on hand truck.
      Item #315
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Photographer's identification stamped recto. In ink, verso, "646 Aunt Eliza's Story." Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 584)
      Staged scene: same women and location as 314, women stand in semicircle, arms raised, four children in front.
      Item #316
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Photographer's identification stamped recto. In ink, verso, "664 Visitors from Carolina." Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 585)
      Staged domestic scene: man and two women in yard. Same location, props as 314 and 316.
      Item #317
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Identification stamped recto. Verso, in ink, "785 Negro Fight." Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 586)
      Staged melee, interior view; nine men and women pretend to brawl in what is clearly a photographer's studio.
      Item #318
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Identification stamped recto. In ink, verso, "687. Aunt Dinah at Home." Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 587)
      Staged domestic scene: Woman washing clothes in washtub next to stove; man stands with broom and bucket nearby.
      Item #319
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Identification stamped recto. Mounted in negative, recto, "611 the Morning's Catch." Advertisement for the American Tobacco Company stamped verso. Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 588)
      Men stand before stalls and barrels holding strings of fish.
      Item #320
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Identification stamped recto. In ink, verso, "Home Life among the Negroes." Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 589)
      Woman washes clothes behind tenement building, clothes hang on line, children, blurred figures at left.
      Item #321
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Identification stamped recto. In ink, verso, "The Interrupted Game." Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 590)
      Eight children kneel in sand at stern of hull of large beached vessel, woman in apron stands behind them.
      Item #322
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Identification stamped recto. Verso, in ink, "658. No one at home." Stereograph ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 591)
      Young boy in tattered clothes standing on step.
      Item #323
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Identification stamped recto. In ink, verso, "719. 4 Kings 7 up." Stereograph ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 592)
      Staged card game: six boys wearing derbies, playing cards. Same location as 319.
      Item #324
    - Alfred S. Campbell, Elizabeth, NJ Identification stamped recto. In ink, verso, "772. [?] Seben" Stereograph, ivory card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 593)
      Staged fight: same group as 324, four boys pounce of fifth who lies prone on the floor.
      Item #325
    - Rufus Morgan, Charlotte, NC Mounted verso, "Characteristic Sketches of Southern Life. No. 503. Where it takes one to do the Work and two to see it Well Done." Stereograph, yellow card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 594)
      Three men, one bent over ax, posing beside small pile of wood in street.
      Item #326
    - J.C. Moulton, Fitchburg, MA (publisher) Mounted verso, "John Brown's Grave, at North Elba, NY. No. 21. 'when I die, bury me by the big rock where I love to sit and read the word of God.' 'And his spirit goes marching on.'" Stereograph, gold card, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 595)
      Tombstone, set before a large rock, commemorating three generations: Captain JOHN BROWN, JOHN BROWN, OLIVER BROWN
      Item #327
    - F.A. Knowell, Charleston, SC Identification stamped recto. "Charleston & Vicinity." Stereograph, gold card, circa 1870 (Box 12, Folder 596)
      Man viewed through trees, appears to be seated in a boat at edge of swamp. Catalogue of views 1-70 stamped verso.
      Item #328
    - Studio unknown "Ruins, Fort Matanzas" stamped into negative, recto. "Southern Gems. By the Florida Club." stamped recto on card. Stereograph, orange card, circa 1868 (Box 12, Folder 597)
      Man with rifle stands in tall grass near massive crumbling brick wall.
      Item #329
    - W.H. Cushing, St. Augustine, FL Stamped recto, "Scenes in Florida. No. 49. Inmates of Colored Home." Stereograph, green card, circa 1870 (Box 12, Folder 598)
      Six women, two men sit on porch and steps of house. Two younger women in attendance. Stamped verso, catalogue of views in series listed 1-96.
      Item #330
    - The Universal Photo Arts Co., Philadelphia; Naperville, Ill. Stamped recto, "5541. Interior of Bates, Hall, Boston Free Library." Stereograph grey card, 1901 (Box 12, Folder 599)
      Large reading room, high ceiling, patrons reading at desks.
      Item #331
    - Crossmon House Photographic Studio, A.C. McIntyre & Co., Jefferson County, NY Mounted verso, "Scenery among the Thousand Islands on the River St. Lawrence." Stereograph, orange card, circa 1867 (Box 12, Folder 600)
      Exterior group portrait: a dozen young men and women in forest setting. Pencil verso: "Jubilee Singers".
      Item #332
    - Published by J.F. Mears, Palatka, FL Identification stamped recto. Stereograph, orange card, circa 1870 (Box 12, Folder 601)
      Two barefoot boys in coats and hats sit astride a dead alligator, its mouth propped wide open.
      Item #333
    - Rufus Morgan, Charlotte, NC Mounted verso, "Characteristic Sketches of Southern Life. No. 504. 'Gossipping (sic) by the way.'" Stereograph, yellow card, 1874 August 14 (Box 12, Folder 602)
      Man astride burro addresses three men standing in field next to burro hitched to a plow. Oval date stamp, verso, "Geo. W. Nason, Jr. Aug 14, 1874, New Bernie, N.C."
      Item #334
    - C. Seaver, Jr., (photographer) Published by Chas Pollock, Boston Stamped recto, "The Southern Series. Jacksonville, Florida. No 47. The Cook." Stereograph, yellow card, circa 1870 (Box 12, Folder 603)
      Woman in apron, with back to picket fence stands holding book in right
      Item #335
    - William A. Rau, Publisher, Philadelphia Stamped recto in negative, "The Johnstown Disaster. 6200. Relief Station Johnstown Station, P.R.R." Stereograph, ivory card, circa 1880 (Box 12, Folder 604)
      Railroad platform with crowd; tracks in foreground. Stamped recto,"Wm. H. Rau, Publisher, Phila, Pa. Sold only by Griffith & Griffith, Philadelphia."
      Item #336
    - S.R. Stoddard, Glens Falls, NY. (publisher) "The 'Garrison' Fort William Henry." Stereograph, orange card, circa 1880 (Box 12, Folder 605)
      Man sits on canon holding cooling sponge. Stamped recto in negative, "73." Stamped verso, "Lake George Views" with catalogue of scenes from No. 50-113. "73. The 'Garrison,' Fort William Henry" underlined.
      Item #337
    - J.F. Jarvis, Washington D.C. Stamped recto, "Lincoln Statue" Stereograph, ivory card, circa 1877 (Box 12, Folder 606)
      Statue: Abraham Lincoln, book in right hand, stands with left hand outstretched over kneeling slave (modeled by Archer Alexander) in loin-cloth. Engraved at base of statue, "EMANCIPATION." Park in background, man sits on bench wearing straw hat. In ink, verso, a copy of the inscription at base of statue.
      Item #338
    - E. Totherick Same statue as item #338. Different angle, date. Stereograph, yellow card, undated (Box 12, Folder 607)
      Mounted verso, "Lincoln Monument, Lincoln Park. No. E. Totherick, Photo." Stamped recto, "J.F. Jarvis Stereoscopic Views, Washington, D.C."
      Item #339
    - J.F. Jarvis, Washington, D.C. Same view as item #338, no one sitting on bench behind statue. Stereograph, ivory card, circa 1877 (Box 12, Folder 608)
      Stamped recto, "J.F. Jarvis' Stereoscopic Views, 185 Penn. Ave. Wash'n, D.C. Lincoln Statue."
      Item #340
    - J.F. Jarvis, Washington, DC Washington's tomb. Stereograph, yellow card, circa 1870 (Box 12, Folder 609)
      Mounted verso, "MOUNT VERNON. Once the home and now the resting place of the immortal Washington...." Stamped verso, "A. Huron"
      Item #341
    - A.F. Styles (publisher), Burlington, VT Two men seated on ground in forest setting. Stereograph, yellow card, circa 1870 (Box 12, Folder 610)
      Two men seated on ground in forest setting. Stamped recto, beneath image, "Guides. Mat. Nick. Entrance to Mammoth Cave, KY." Duplicate: 1970.
      Item #342
    - A.F. Styles, Burlington, VT Stamped recto, "Scenes in Florida. 635. Subject for Reconstruction." Stereograph, yellow card, circa 1872 (Box 12, Folder 611)
      Man and child sit in doorway of crudely built wooden shack.
      Item #343
    - A.F. Styles, Burlington, VT Stamped recto, "Scenes in Florida. 630. The Alligator Party." Stereograph, yellow card, circa 1880 (Box 12, Folder 612)
      Black man stands at left, looking right, holding oar; four white men with rifles sit in beached boat, looking left; adult and baby alligator lie in foreground.
      Item #344
    - George Barker, Niagara Falls, NY "The Lighting Express-Savannah Georgia." Stereograph, ivory card, 1886 (Box 12, Folder 613)
      Bullock cart with driver in derby hat, town street; horse in harness in background.
      Item #345
    - George Barker, Niagara Falls, NY "Florida. Harvesting the Cocoa-nuts" Stereograph, ivory card, 1881 (Box 12, Folder 614)
      Man stands among coconut trees, long hook on his shoulder, pile of coconuts foreground. Stamped recto, around perimeter of card, list of prizes and awards won by the photographer.
      Item #346
    - D.W. Kelley (publisher) Chicago; Dallas, TX.; Atlanta, GA. "How de Debil Do Dey Make a Bicycle? 4628" Stereograph, grey card, 1895 (Box 12, Folder 615)
      Two boys sit in grass: one with mallet, broken umbrella, piece of wood tied with string, the other watches. Woman in background.
      Item #347
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; St. Louis, MO. Copyright B.L. Singley "9175 -- Sponge Market, Key West Harbor, Fla., U.S.A." Stereograph, pink card, 1898 (Box 12, Folder 616)
      Men gathered around piles of sponges on dock; boats and horse drawn wagon in background. Label stamped in six different languages, verso.
      Item #348
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; and other cities. Copyright B.L. Singley "9323 Cutting Timber in the State of Washington, U.S.A." Stereograph, pink card, 1898 (Box 12, Folder 617)
      Forest scene: two men chop tree from opposite sides with large double-headed axes. Two others background. Title stamped in six languages verso along with long descriptive text.
      Item #349
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA, St. Louis, MO. Copyright B.L. Singley. "9128 Troop K, 10th U.S. Cavalry, on the March, Chickamauga, Ga., U.S.A." Stereograph, pink card, 1898 (Box 12, Folder 618)
      Company of men on horseback and in cavalry uniform approaches along road.
      Item #350
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; and other cities "115 - 16738 Mining Phosphate and Loading Cars Near Columbia, Tenn." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1898 (Box 13, Folder 619)
      Men in ditch pile dirt near rail tracks; men at tracks load dirt into boxcars. Long descriptive text stamped verso. Duplicates 357.
      Item #351
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; and other cities "109 - 314. Old Slave Market, St. Augustine, Florida." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1925 (Box 13, Folder 620)
      Open air pavilion; people sitting, or passing through; car in street in foreground, man with straw hat at wheel. Long descriptive text stamped verso.
      Item #352
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; and other cities. "16 - 13740. Harvesting Indian River Pineapples in Florida." Stereograph, grey card, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 621)
      Half a dozen men harvest pineapples in field and load filled baskets onto small flatbed railcar. Long descriptive text stamped verso.
      Item #353
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; and other cities. Copyright B.L. Singley "278. Harvesting Cocoanuts, Lake Worth, Fla., U.S.A." Stereograph, grey card, 1893 (Box 13, Folder 622)
      Man with long forked stick stands beneath tree beside pile of coconuts. Long descriptive text stamped verso.
      Item #354
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; and other cities "8067. The New South" Stereograph, grey card, circa 1898 (Box 13, Folder 623)
      Group portrait: a couple: black woman and white man sit on porch steps surrounded by 13 children and young adults.
      Item #355
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Chicago, IL; London, ENG. "P147 - 18206. The Blacksmith's Shop." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1896 (Box 13, Folder 624)
      White man with apron, tool behind his back stands near center of shop. Black boy holding whisk sits on barrel at right. Tools, wheels, horseshoes, etc. lie scattered about. Long description stamped verso.
      Item #356
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Chicago, IL; London, ENG "115 - 16738. Mining Phosphate and Loading Cars Near Columbia, Tenn." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1896 (Box 13, Folder 625)
      Duplicate of item #351.
      Item #357
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Chicago, IL; London, ENG "106 - 13722. Rosin on the Docks, Savannah, Ga." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1896 (Box 13, Folder 626)
      Hundreds of barrels standing upright. Man tapping or repairing barrel in foreground. Background, ship masts and buildings. Long descriptive text stamped verso.
      Item #358
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Portland, OR; London, ENG "85 - 6952. Gathering Peaches, Delaware." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1896 (Box 13, Folder 627)
      Peach orchard: pickers at work, full baskets, man on donkey overseeing operation. Long descriptive text stamped verso.
      Item #359
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Portland, OR; London, ENG; Sydney, AUS. Copyright 1904 B.L. Singley, Copyright 1911, Keystone View Company "113 - 13751. Hoeing Rice in South Carolina, U.S.A." Stereograph, grey card, 1912 (Box 13, Folder 628)
      Over a dozen men and women hoeing, or standing with hoes in large field. Long description stamped verso.
      Item #360
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Chicago, IL; London, ENG. "50 - 13365. America's Most Notable Gathering of Military Heroes -- Left to Right: Jacques (Belgium), Diaz (Italy), Coolidge, Foche (France), Pershing, end, Beatty (England) at his right." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1920 (Box 13, Folder 629)
      National Convention of the American Legion at Kansas City, 1921. Military Allied commanders from WWI stand in row on raised stage with Vice President Coolidge. Crowds of spectators, foreground.
      Item #361
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Portland, OR; London, ENG "118 - 16771. Harvesting Peanuts, Marianna, Ark." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1915 (Box 13, Folder 630)
      Group of black men and women stand in semicircle holding peanut vines, facing plantation owner who stands at left; center, white woman in white bonnet sits on pile of peanut vines on pole, handfuls in her lap; two dogs, foreground; deep background, upright pole with vines, buildings. Long descriptive text stamped verso.
      Item #362
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Chicago, IL; London, ENG "P215 - V22091. Cars Loaded with Cotton Bales on Levee Near Cotton Growing District, Texas." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1915 (Box 13, Folder 631)
      Men with hand trucks loading bales of cotton into rail cars. Bridge in back ground. Long descriptive text stamped verso.
      Item #363
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Chicago, IL; London, ENG "49 - 23306." 'Back to Home Land!' Removing the Casket of America's Unknown Soldier from the Olympia, Washington, D.C." Stereograph, circa 1919 (Box 13, Folder 632)
      Pallbearers hold flag-draped coffin at end of gangway; dignitaries and officers lined up nearby; men on deck hold hats over left breast. Long descriptive text stamped verso.
      Item #364
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Portland, OR; London, ENG; Sydney, AUS "19171. 'Present Arms'-Colored Soldiers of the 8th Illinois Infantry." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1917 (Box 13, Folder 633)
      Company of black soldiers lined up, shoulder to shoulder, at curb of city street, parallel to street; facing right, rifles held in front. Awning over sidewalk, "Laundry."
      Item #365
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Portland, OR; London, ENG; "19118. Uncle Sam Provides for Comfort of his Soldiers. Colored Troops en Route to France Taking Train [indistinguishable] at Railway Division Point." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1917 (Box 13, Folder 634)
      Black troopers in formation facing left; no weapons; officers in front. Giant billboard in background, "This is [blocked out] Unexcelled Opportunities Offered Manufacturers for Building Sites -- Chamber of Commerce."
      Item #366
    - Keystone View Company, Meadville, PA; New York, NY; Portland, OR; London, ENG Sydney, AUS "19107. Supper is Ready and the Boys are Hungry -- Colored Troops Lined Up for Mess." Stereograph, grey card, circa 1917 (Box 13, Folder 635)
      Black troops each holding tin cup and plate, lined up in road, barracks in background.
      Item #367
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH "6678. Drill of the Charleston Cadets, Charleston, S.C., U.S.A." Stereograph, pink card, circa 1890 (Box 13, Folder 636)
      Cadets parade four abreast across city square; black woman with two small white children in stroller stands foreground watching them pass; other black and white children stand nearby.
      Item #368
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH "6907 Well 'Rastus, If I Don't See You No Moah, de Mule's Your'n." Stereograph, grey card, 1891 (Box 13, Folder 637)
      Two black men shake hands, apparently parting; one with traveling case, the other holds horse by bridle; a watermelon lies at his feet.
      Item #369
    - Kilburn Brothers, Littleton, NH "885. Cabin Home, Petersburg, Va." Stereograph, yellow card, circa 1890 (Box 13, Folder 638)
      Small log cabin: two men and a woman stand out front; two small children sit on ground; washtub, kettle, and bucket nearby.
      Item #370
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH "6946. Morning Start in the Cotton Field." Stereograph, pink card, circa 1895 (Box 13, Folder 639)
      More than a dozen black men and women, perhaps two adolescents, pick cotton in large field; two white men on horse back watch.
      Item #371
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH "14532. Cake Walk at the Old Plantation, Pan American Exposition." Stereograph, pink card, 1896? (Box 13, Folder 640)
      Group of performers performing cake walk.
      Item #372
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH "14315. It's So Easy To Be Lazy" Stereograph, pink card, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 641)
      Young black boy, smiling, sits astride small pony.
      Item #373
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH "457. Cotton Pickers, Florida, U.S.A." Copyright 1879. Stereograph, pink card (Box 13, Folder 642)
      A dozen men and women, very old to quite young, standing in cotton field posing for picture.
      Item #374
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH Copyright 1901 James M. Davis: New York, St. Louis, Liverpool, Toronto, Sydney "14565. The Last Sad Homecoming. At The Depot Canton, O." Stereograph, pink card (Box 13, Folder 643)
      Flag draped coffin being removed from elegant hearse. Pallbearers, men in uniform including sailor, foreground. Dignitaries, hats over left breast, stand nearby. Deep background, tall chimney belching smoke.
      Item #375
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH Copyright 1892. "7026 Baked Possum in Prospect." Stereograph, pink card (Box 13, Folder 644)
      Hunting party: man stands left holding quarry; two others sit on log rifles resting against knees; turkey lies on ground in front.
      Item #376
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH Copyright 1879 "460. Cotton Gin in full blast, Florida." Stereograph, ivory card (Box 13, Folder 645)
      Many people, black and white outside gin; at least one wagonload of cotton visible at side of building.
      Item #377
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH Copyright 1879 "456. Picking Cotton, Fla." Stereograph, ivory card (Box 13, Folder 646)
      Eight adults and children, men and women stand in cotton field.
      Item #378
    - B.W. Kilburn, Littleton, NH Copyright 1901 "14309. Down in Sunny Tennessee." Stereograph, pink card (Box 13, Folder 647)
      Fourteen children, boys and girls, dressed in "Sunday best," most with hats stand before door to house.
      Item #379
    - L.M. Williams, Columbia, PA Lady stands balancing washtub on her head, washboard under right arm, holding bucket with left. Stereograph, yellow card, circa 1860 (Box 13, Folder 648)
      In ink, verso, "Black Womon" (sic).
      Item #380
    - C.W. Woodward, Rochester, NY "1482. Howard University, Washington, D.C." Stereograph, orange card, 1875 (Box 13, Folder 649)
      Grand, magnificent looking building; many people, well dressed stand out front; figures on balcony and at windows.
      Item #381
    - Underwood & Underwood, New York, London, Toronto - Canada, Ottawa - Kansas "(32) 'Keep the Flag in their hands and Patriotism will stay in their hearts" -Words of William McKinley, El Paso, Texas." Stereograph, pink card, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 650)
      Parade: Children and adults march down street; sea of U.S. flags; man on horseback pointing directions. Sign foreground, being carried by marchers, "$75,000 to be Expended for new Schoolhouses this year." Stamped verso, "Winthrop."
      Item #382